Shoot me.
‫أطلقي النار عليّ.‬
So, are you all ready? There's no need to be nervous.
‫هل أنتما مستعدان؟ لا داعي للتوتر.‬
Your hairband is crooked. I'll fix it for you.
‫طوق الشعر مائل. سأعدّله لك.‬
Now, smile.
‫الآن، ابتسمي.‬
That's the way. Very pretty.
‫أجل، هكذا. ما أجملك.‬
Okay, now. Hold my hand.
‫حسنًا. والآن أمسكي بيدي.‬
All right, then. Let's go.
‫حسنًا إذًا. هيا بنا.‬
The Lieberts, who defected from East Germany a few days ago,
‫آل "ليبرت" الذين انشقوا‬ ‫عن "ألمانيا الشرقية" قبل بضعة أيام،‬
have appeared together as a family for the press.
‫ظهروا للصحافة معًا كعائلة.‬
Mr. and Mrs. Liebert didn't appear tired,
‫لم يبد السيد والسيدة "ليبرت" متعبين،‬
and their fraternal twins both appeared happy.
‫وبدا التوأم سعيدين.‬
Mr. Liebert, how do you like it in the West?
‫كيف تجد الغرب هنا يا سيد "ليبرت"؟‬
It's actually rather complicated.
‫الأمر معقد في حقيقة الأمر.‬
Why?
‫لماذا؟‬
When I realize that I'm free to speak as I please,
‫عندما أدركت أنني حرّ في التعبير عمّا أريده،‬
it's difficult to find the words to say.
‫وجدت صعوبة في انتقاء ما أقوله من كلام.‬
Is that right?
‫حقًا؟‬
But to answer your question, just look at the smiles
‫لكن للإجابة عن سؤالك،‬ ‫انظر فحسب إلى الابتسامة،‬
on the faces of my wife and children.
‫التي تعتلي وجه زوجتي والولدين.‬
Yes, it appears so.
‫صحيح، على ما يبدو.‬
Can you please tell us about what life is like in the East now?
‫أيمكنك أن تخبرنا من فضلك‬ ‫عن أحوال الحياة في الشرق الآن؟‬
Johan, what are you doing?
‫ماذا تفعل يا "يوهان"؟‬
Johan?
‫"يوهان"؟‬
Which is it in?
‫في أي يد هي؟‬
This one.
‫هذه.‬
That's right.
‫هذا صحيح.‬
Here. It's yours, Anna.
‫هاك. إنها لك يا "آنا".‬
Yay! An acorn!
‫يا للروعة! إنها جوزة بلوط!‬
Okay, one more time. Which is it in?
‫حسنًا، مرة أخرى. في أي يد هي؟‬
This one.
‫هذه.‬
Right again.
‫أصبت مجددًا.‬
Here. It's yours, Anna.
‫هاك. إنها لك يا "آنا".‬
Wow!
‫يا للروعة!‬
Johan, open up both your hands.
‫افتح كلتا يديك يا "يوهان".‬
Aw, you're kidding.
‫أنت تمزح.‬
I would've won either way.
‫كنت لأفوز بأي حال.‬
That's right.
‫هذا صحيح.‬
You see, all the acorns here are yours, Anna.
‫كل تلك الحبّات لك أنت يا "آنا".‬
Hey, Johan, did you see the town from the car on our way here?
‫"يوهان"، هل رأيت البلدة من السيارة‬ ‫ونحن في طريقنا إلى هنا؟‬
It's way different than on the other side.
‫إنها مختلفة تمامًا عن الجانب الآخر.‬
There were lots of pretty shops. And there are lots of clothes and toys.
‫ثمة الكثير من المتاجر الرائعة‬ ‫والكثير من الملابس والألعاب.‬
You saw it too, right, Johan?
‫رأيتها أنت أيضًا، أليس كذلك يا "يوهان"؟‬
Yeah, I saw it.
‫نعم، رأيتها.‬
They're all yours too, Anna.
‫كلّها لك أيضًا يا "آنا".‬
They are?
‫حقًا؟‬
They sure are.
‫بالتأكيد.‬
How come they're mine?
‫كيف لها أن تكون لي؟‬
Just because.
‫ستكون لك فحسب.‬
I saw you on TV, Mr. Liebert.
‫رأيتك على التلفاز يا سيد "ليبرت".‬
Anyway, come inside.
‫لا يهم، ادخل.‬
Johan, did someone come?
‫هل أتى أحد يا "يوهان"؟‬
Johan.
‫"يوهان".‬
Johan?
‫"يوهان"؟‬
Johan…
‫"يوهان"…‬
Did you… do this, Johan?
‫هل أنت من فعل هذا يا "يوهان"؟‬
And the ones before?
‫وما قبلها؟‬
When Uncle Josef and Aunt Klara died,
‫موت العم "جوزيف" والعمة "كلارا"،‬
and when Mr. Baedeker died, you did all those too?
‫وموت السيد "باديكر"،‬ ‫هل أنت المتسبب في ذلك أيضًا؟‬
Today was special.
‫قضينا اليوم يومًا مميزًا.‬
Did you do it?
‫هل أنت من فعل هذا؟‬
You see, the monster came today.
‫أتى الوحش اليوم.‬
You killed all of them, didn't you, Johan?
‫قتلتهم جميعًا، أليس كذلك يا "يوهان"؟‬
The monster came to take us away.
‫أتى الوحش لأخذنا بعيدًا.‬
Put out your hands.
‫مدّي يديك.‬
Shoot me.
‫أطلقي عليّ النار.‬
After you shoot me, wipe off the gun with a cloth and toss it out the window.
‫بعد إطلاق النار عليّ،‬ ‫امسحي المسدس بقطعة قماش وارميه من النافذة.‬
Make sure you shoot me in the head.
‫احرصي على أن تصيبني في رأسي.‬
After you shoot me, run away.
‫بعد إطلاق النار، اهربي.‬
Run as fast as you can so the monster doesn't catch you.
‫اهربي سريعًا بقدر استطاعتك،‬ ‫كي لا يمسك بك الوحش.‬
Don't worry. Even when I'm dead, you are me and I am you.
‫لا تقلقي، فحتى بعد موتي،‬ ‫ستكونين أنا وأكون أنت.‬
That night… That rainy night, someone came.
‫في تلك الليلة الممطرة، ثمة شخص قد أتى.‬
Nina…
‫"نينا"…‬
Someone came to the mansion.
‫أتى شخص ما إلى القصر.‬
Someone… Someone came. Who were they?
‫أتى شخص ما. من كان؟‬
The monster came.
‫أتى الوحش.‬
Nina!
‫"نينا"!‬
What a mess!
‫يا لها من فوضى!‬
How come this mansion caught fire?
‫كيف احترق هذا القصر؟‬
Nobody was living here, right?
‫لم يكن يعيش فيه أحد؟‬
They think it was arson.
‫يظنون أنه بفعل فاعل.‬
That's disturbing.
‫يا للحيرة.‬
Dr. Tenma.
‫د. "تينما".‬
Will you please come with us?
‫هلّا ترافقنا.‬
General Wolf wants to see you.
‫يريد الجنرال "وولف" أن يراك.‬
General… Wolf…
‫الجنرال "وولف"…‬
General Wolf.
‫حضرة الجنرال "وولف".‬
Dr. Tenma?
‫د. "تينما"؟‬
Yes.
‫نعم.‬
So, you were summoned as well.
‫اُستدعيت أنت أيضًا.‬
I got a letter from Johan saying, "I'll be waiting at the Red Rose Mansion."
‫تلقيت رسالة من "يوهان" كُتب فيها، "سأنتظرك‬ ‫في قصر (الوردة الحمراء)".‬
But just getting to this hospital here in Prague was the best I could do.
‫لكن لم يسعني إلا القدوم إلى هذه المستشفى‬ ‫هنا في "براغ".‬
Did you get a letter as well?
‫تلقيت أنت أيضًا رسالة؟‬
It's so ironic.
‫إنه لأمر مثير للسخرية.‬
Now the only person who ever writes letters to me anymore is Johan.
‫ما عاد أحد يراسلني إلا "يوهان".‬
Try not to talk so much.
‫حاول ألّا تتكلّم كثيرًا.‬
I was born into a military family.
‫وُلدت في عائلة عسكرية.‬
It was part of my destiny to be one of the elite.
‫كان قدري أن أصبح من النخبة.‬
But now, the only person who knows who I am is that monster.
‫لكن الوحيد الذي يعرفني الآن هو ذلك الوحش.‬
I heard that the Red Rose Mansion burned down.
‫سمعت أن قصر "الوردة الحمراء" قد أُحرق.‬
I bet that at this very moment, they're coming into the light of day.
‫أنا متأكد من أنهم في هذه اللحظة،‬ ‫قد تجلوا إلى ضوء النهار.‬
Those people whose names were stolen just like mine was.
‫من سُلبت أسماؤهم مثلي.‬
Have you identified where the fire started?
‫هل توصلت إلى الموضع الذي ابتدأ منه الحريق؟‬
Yes. It seems to have been in a large hall on the second floor.
‫نعم. يبدو أنه اندلع‬ ‫في بهو كبير في الطابق الثاني.‬
Since the flames were most intense there, kerosene or gas must have been used.
‫نظرًا لأن اللهيب كان أشد هناك،‬ ‫فلا بد أن الكيروسين أو الغاز قد استُخدم.‬
Kerosene?
‫كيروسين؟‬
So, it was arson, huh?
‫كان إحراقًا متعمدًا إذًا؟‬
We won't know for sure until we investigate further.
‫لن نتأكد إلا بعد أجراء المزيد من التحريات.‬
But a wall of the hall was torn down.
‫لكن ثمة جدار في البهو قد هُدم.‬
What's that about?
‫ما قصته؟‬
I don't know.
‫لا أعرف.‬
Sir! Come quick!
‫سيدي! تعال بسرعة!‬
What's wrong?
‫ما الخطب؟‬
What's this?
‫ما هذا؟‬
I saw something under the rose bush, then when I dug,
‫ثمة ما رأيته تحت شجيرات الورد،‬ ‫وبعدما بدأت الحفر،‬
I just kept on finding more and more.
‫بقيت أجد المزيد والمزيد منها.‬
After all these years,
‫بعد كلّ تلك السنوات،‬
they'll finally come to the light of day.
‫تجلوا أخيرًا إلى ضوء النهار.‬
But there's no longer anyone alive who knows their names.
‫لكن ما من أحد قد بقي حيًا‬ ‫ممّن يعرفون أسماءهم.‬
Oh, my goodness!
‫يا للهول!‬
It's completely burned down.
‫أُحرق تمامًا.‬
This mansion was our only clue to Tenma's whereabouts, but now…
‫كان هذا القصر دليلنا الوحيد‬ ‫الذي سيقودنا إلى مكان "تينما" ولكننا الآن…‬
Out of the way! Coming through! Move!
‫تنحوا عن الطريق! أنا قادم! تحرّكوا!‬
What's that about?
‫ما الذي يحدث؟‬
Contact HQ! It's an emergency!
‫صلني بالقيادة المركزية! إنها حالة طارئة!‬
We've found a bunch of human bones!
‫وجدنا عظامًا بشرية!‬
46 people?
‫46 شخصًا؟‬
Yes. That's what I heard.
‫نعم. هذا ما سمعته.‬
In 1981,
‫في عام 1981،‬
46 people suddenly disappeared from that mansion.
‫اختفى فجأة 46 شخصًا في ذلك القصر.‬
At the time, that was all the information I could get in East Germany.
‫آنذاك، كانت تلك كلّ المعلومات التي أمكنني‬ ‫الحصول عليها في "ألمانيا الشرقية".‬
An experiment was being conducted at that mansion.
‫كانت تُجرى في ذلك القصر تجربة.‬
An experiment…
‫تجربة…‬
Back up!
‫تراجعوا!‬
This is my theory.
‫هذه نظريتي.‬
Get these onlookers out of here!
‫أخرجوا المتفرجين من هنا!‬
I believe that is where that child was born.
‫أعتقد أن ذلك الطفل قد وُلد هناك.‬
Johan… I'm cold.
‫أنا أشعر بالبرد يا "يوهان".‬
I can't walk anymore.
‫ما عدت قادرة على المشي.‬
I'm so hungry.
‫أنا أتضور جوعًا.‬
Johan, will we… die?
‫هل سنموت يا "يوهان"؟‬
Johan, say my name.
‫انطق اسمي يا "يوهان".‬
Say my name.
‫انطق اسمي.‬
We don't have names.
‫ما من اسم لنا.‬
My name…
‫اسمي…‬
-Get some blankets. -Yes, sir.
‫- أحضر بطانيتين.‬ ‫- حاضر يا سيدي.‬
-And something warm to drink.
‫- ومشروبًا ساخنًا.‬ ‫- أمرك يا سيدي.‬
THE NAMELESS MONSTER
‫"(وحش بلا اسم)"‬
"Such a shame because Johan was such a wonderful name."
‫"كم هذا مؤسف، إذ أن اسم (يوهان) رائع."‬
Johan…
‫"يوهان"…‬
Those children didn't have names.
‫لم يكن لهذين الطفلين اسمين.‬
When I gave him the name Johan,
‫عندما سمّيته "يوهان"،‬
it must have awakened something inside him.
‫لا بد أن ثمة ما أيقظته بداخله.‬
All this talk of the past is meaningless.
‫لا جدوى من التحدّث عن الماضي.‬
Let's talk about the future.
‫لنتحدّث عن المستقبل.‬
Though I have no future.
‫مع أنه ليس لي مستقبل.‬
That's enough, General Wolf. Don't talk anymore.
‫هذا يكفي يا جنرال "وولف". لا تتحدّث.‬
Eva Heinemann is…
‫"إيفا هاينمان"…‬
Eva Heinemann is with the other members of our organization.
‫"إيفا هاينمان" مع الأعضاء الآخرين‬ ‫من منظمتنا.‬
Our organization was made up of four people.
‫كانت منظمتنا مؤلّفة من أربعة أشخاص.‬
There was the murdered Professor Goedelitz and me.
‫كنت أنا والبروفيسور "غيدليست" الذي قُتل‬ ‫من بينهم.‬
Eva is with the other two.
‫و"إيفا" مع الشخصين الآخرين.‬
They're trying to use Eva.
‫إنهما يحاولان استغلال "إيفا".‬
We can't let them meet.
‫يجب أن نمنعهم من الالتقاء ببعضهما بعضًا.‬
Whether I'm dead or alive,
‫سواء أن عشت أم مت،‬
there's no stopping it.
‫فلا مجال لدرع ما يحدث.‬
It's about to go out of control.
‫تكاد الأوضاع أن تخرج عن السيطرة.‬
You have to stop it.
‫يجب أن توقف ما سيحدث.‬
You have to save us, Tenma!
‫يجب أن تنقذنا يا "تينما"!‬
Dr. Tenma!
‫د. "تينما"!‬
My name is Helmut.
‫اسمي "هيلموت".‬
Helmut Wolf.
‫"هيلموت وولف".‬
The people who knew me as Helmut…
‫من يعرفونني باسم "هيلموت"…‬
are no longer alive.
‫ما عادوا أحياءً.‬
Say my name.
‫انطق اسمي.‬
That proves that I lived.
‫إذ يثبت ذلك أنني عشت.‬
Helmut.
‫"هيلموت".‬
Say my name.
‫انطق اسمي.‬
Helmut!
‫"هيلموت"!‬
You are Helmut Wolf!
‫أنت "هيلموت وولف".‬
This must be… the landscape that Johan saw.
‫لا بد أن ذلك هو المكان الذي رآه "يوهان".‬
A world where there are no names.
‫مكان لا أسماء فيه.‬
General Wolf…
‫حضرة الجنرال "وولف"…‬
It's burned down.
‫لقد أُحرق.‬
The gate is locked too.
‫البوابة مقفلة أيضًا.‬
The police are probably keeping people out.
‫على الأرجح أن الشرطة تبعد الناس عن المكان.‬
You can't open it.
‫لن يسعك فتحها.‬
Mr. Lipský…
‫سيد "ليبسكي"…‬
I know that this was important to you
‫أعرف أنه كان له أهمية لك،‬
since you listened to book readings here as a child.
‫إذ كنت تسمع قراءات الكتب فيه في طفولتك.‬
-But-- -Nina.
‫- لكن…‬ ‫- "نينا".‬
It was important to you as well.
‫كان له أهمية بالنسبة إليك أيضًا.‬
It could have been a place that would revive your memories.
‫قد يساعدك المكان على استعادة ذكرياتك.‬
My vision…
‫رؤياي…‬
of the great hall in this mansion filled with bodies lying in a heap…
‫عن بهو هذا القصير الكبير الذي امتلأ‬ ‫بالأجساد المُكوّمة على بعضها بعضًا…‬
dead.
‫والتي كانت ميتة.‬
The vision you saw, Nina, it happened, didn't it?
‫الرؤيا التي راودتك يا "نينا"‬ ‫هي لحدث قد وقع، أليس كذلك؟‬
I was surprised when I saw the news.
‫فاجأني ما رأيته في الأخبار.‬
They said they found 46 skeletons at the Red Rose Mansion.
‫قيل إنهم وجدوا 46 هيكلًا عظميًا‬ ‫في قصر "الوردة الحمراء".‬
It was just like your brother Johan told you, wasn't it?
‫كما أخبرك أخاك "يوهان" بالضبط، أليس كذلك؟‬
What did my brother Johan see?
‫ما الذي رآه أخي "يوهان"؟‬
A horrific sight… True fear…
‫منظر مرعب وخوف حقيقي…‬
If I had been there… at that time…
‫لو كنت هناك في ذلك الوقت…‬
I would have turned into a monster.
‫لتحوّلت إلى وحش.‬
Nina, it may be good that this place burned down.
‫لعلّه خيرًا أن هذا المكان أُحرق يا "نينا".‬
I thought it would be more difficult for me.
‫حسبت أنني سأواجه صعوبة أكبر.‬
I thought I wouldn't be able to live if this place disappeared.
‫حسبت أنني ما كنت لأتمكن من أن أعيش‬ ‫إن اختفى هذا المكان.‬
But I don't feel that way now.
‫لكنني لا أشعر بذلك الآن.‬
That's probably because this place held only sad memories.
‫لعلّ السبب أن هذا المكان‬ ‫ما كان فيه إلا الذكريات المحزنة.‬
I wasn't a gifted student.
‫لم أكن طالبًا موهوبًا.‬
That made me sad.
‫وقد أحزنني ذلك.‬
I wasn't able to live up to his expectations.
‫لم أرق إلى مستوى توقعاته.‬
I wished…
‫تمنيت…‬
I wished that I lived up to his expectations.
‫تمنيت لو أنني ارتقيت إلى مستوى توقعاته.‬
But I wasn't able to.
‫لكنني عجزت عن ذلك.‬
I became an unwanted child.
‫أصبحت طفلًا غير مرغوب فيه.‬
Mr. Lipský, do you have a mom and dad?
‫سيد "ليبسكي"، ألديك أب وأم؟‬
Yes. But I've never lived with them.
‫نعم. لكنني لم أعش معهما مطلقًا.‬
Nina…
‫"نينا"…‬
If you regain your memories,
‫إن استعدت ذكرياتك،‬
I hope they're happy memories.
‫فأرجو أن تكون ذكريات سعيدة.‬
Happy memories?
‫ذكريات سعيدة؟‬
That's right. Happy memories.
‫أجل. ذكريات سعيدة.‬
I'm not sure I have any happy memories.
‫لست موقنًا مما إن كانت لديّ ذكريات سعيدة.‬
Tenma once told me…
‫سبق أن أخبرني "تينما"…‬
if you don't have any happy memories, then make them.
‫إن لم تكن لديك ذكريات سعيدة،‬ ‫فأوجدها لنفسك.‬
Tenma told me you can make happy memories.
‫أخبرني "تينما" بأنه يسع المرء‬ ‫أن يوجد لنفسه ذكريات سعيدة.‬
-Dieter, your mouth is covered in ketchup. -So is yours.
‫- "ديتر"، إن فمك مغطى بصلصلة الطماطم.‬ ‫- وكذلك أنت.‬
Nina.
‫"نينا".‬
Yes?
‫نعم؟‬
I'm making a new puppet show.
‫أنا أعمل على تحضير عرضًا للدمى.‬
What's it about?
‫ما قصته؟‬
Nobody's ever liked watching my puppet shows.
‫لم يحب أحد مشاهدة عروض الدمى الخاصة بي.‬
But I think people will like this new one.
‫لكنني أظن أن الناس‬ ‫سيحبون هذا العرض الجديد.‬
Show us your new show!
‫أرنا عرضك الجديد!‬
Yeah! I wanna see it!
‫أجل! أريد رؤيته!‬
I'm a girl who's lost her memories.
‫أنا فتاة قد فقدت ذكرياتها.‬
I dream that a monster is chasing me.
‫أحلم بوحش يطاردني.‬
I dream that I'm chasing a monster.
‫أحلم بأنني أطارد وحشًا.‬
But I love singing.
‫لكنني أحب الغناء.‬
I also love dancing.
‫وأحب الرقص أيضًا.‬
Someday, I'll have a lovely dream.
‫سيراودني ذات يوم حلمًا جميلًا.‬
Someday, that dream will come true.
‫وسيتحقق ذلك الحلم ذات يوم.‬
Someday…
‫ذات يوم…‬
I can't think of what comes next.
‫لا يسعني التفكير فيما قد يلي ذلك.‬
I want the story of this girl to have a happy ending.
‫أريد لقصة الفتاة هذه أن تحظى بنهاية سعيدة.‬
But…
‫ولكن…‬
I can't think of one.
‫أعجز عن التفكير في نهاية.‬
I want it to have a happy ending.
‫أريد أن يكون لها نهاية سعيدة.‬
Thank you.
‫أشكرك.‬
The girl decided to leave on a voyage.
‫قررت الفتاة أن تخرج في رحلة.‬
She does not know what kind of voyage it will be.
‫لا تعرف ما قد يكون نوعها.‬
She does not know what awaits her.
‫لا تعرف ما ينتظرها.‬
But the girl will courageously continue her journey.
‫لكن الفتاة ستكمل رحلتها بشجاعة.‬
The girl turned around and waved again and again.
‫التفت الفتاة وبقيت تلّح بيدها باستمرار.‬
Again and again.
‫واستمرت في التلويح.‬
And then she left…
‫ومن ثم غادرت…‬
In search of a happy ending.
‫بحثًا عن نهاية سعيدة.‬
Nina!
‫"نينا"!‬
Nina! You came--
‫"نينا"! لقد عدت…‬
I've been looking for you, Mr. Lipský.
‫كنت أبحث عنك يا سيد "ليبسكي".‬
You are the son of the owner
‫أنت ابن مالك‬
of the Red Rose Mansion, Franz Bonaparta, aren't you?
‫قصر "الوردة الحمراء"،‬ ‫"فرانس بونابارتا"، أليس كذلك؟‬